{"tossups": [{"question": "This country was the birthplace of the starting shortstop and first baseman for the 2015 Chicago White Sox, Alexei Ramirez and Jose Abreu. The names of players like Yunel Escobar and Yoenis Cespedes, begin with \u201cY,\u201d as inspired by this country\u2019s former ties with diplomats like Yuri Pavlov. For ten points, name this country from which Aroldis Chapman and Yasiel Puig defected, leaving behind the only Communist government in Latin America.", "answer": "<b> Cuba</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One action in this city led to the escalation of Operation Chammal. Twelve people, including Cabu and Charb, were killed in a January 2015 office shooting in this city. The Eagles of Death Metal were interrupted during a performance in this city, though a \u201cdouble-tap\u201d incident was avoided at a friendly soccer match attended by Franccois Hollande. The Bataclan theater was attacked in, for ten points, what city, the site of the January 2015<em> Charlie Hebdo</em> shooting and a November 13th attack claimed by ISIS?", "answer": "<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This leader defeated the Sherden sea pirates on his land\u2019s coast. This ruler commissioned a building with a hypostyle hall to commemorate his rule with his wife Nefertari. This man, who commissioned the Temple of Abu Simbel, signed the world\u2019s first peace treaty with Hittite ruler Hattusili III after winning the largest chariot battle in history at Kadesh. For ten points, name this \u201cgreat\u201d Egyptian pharaoh.", "answer": "<b> Ramses II</b> or<b> Ramses the Great</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This amendment was cited in<em> Presser v. Illinois</em>, which allowed states to ban groups like the ethnic German \u201cInstruct and Defend Association.\u201d The 2010 case<em> McDonald v.</em> <em>Chicago</em> incorporated this amendment to the states after<em> D.C. v. Heller</em> overturned a law requiring \u201ctrigger locks.\u201d The phrase \u201cA well regulated militia\u201d begins, for ten points, what Constitutional amendment that protects the right to\u201ckeep and bear arms?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Second</b> Amendment to the U.S. Constitution", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Brunswick Manifesto was proclaimed by this man\u2019s cousin in an attempt to save this man\u2019s life, and his son is known as the \u201cLost Dauphin\u201d. This king\u2019s wife was involved in the Affair of the Diamond Necklace, and his failure to consummate his marriage with that woman was due to his phimosis. After dismissing Jacques Necker, this monarch faced the Women\u2019s March on Versailles, after which he was held captive in Paris. For ten points, name this husband of Marie Antoinette, a French monarch who was guillotined during the French Revolution.", "answer": "King<b> Louis XVI</b> (prompt on Louis)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The Battle of Amiens occurred during an offensive named for this many days, which saw the breaking of the Hindenburg Line. This number of days also names a period that began when a certain man landed near Cannes after escaping from exile on Elba. That period of this length was ended by Napoleon\u2019s defeat at Waterloo. For ten points, name this number, which names a really long war between France and England.", "answer": "<b> 100</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "While attempting to perform this action, David Sharp died near the corpse of \u201cGreen Boots,\u201d which was visible from 2006 until his burial in 2014. The Japanese comedian Ayako Imoto gave up her effort to do this after a 2014 disaster on the Khumbu Icefall. When asked why he would attempt this action, George Mallory responded, \u201cBecause it\u2019s there.\u201d Tenzing Norgay and Edmund Hillary were the first recorded people to perform, for ten points, what landmark feat in mountaineering in Nepal?", "answer": "<b> Climb</b>ing Mt.<b> Everest</b> (accept descriptions)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During this war, the<em> Santa Fe</em> was captured near King Edward Point. A year after losing this war, a military junta led by Jorge Videla lost power. A nuclear submarine sunk the<em> General Belgrano</em> during this war, which was sparked by the raising of a flag on South Georgia Island. For ten points, name this 1982 war won by the British over the Islas Malvinas, a small group of islands near Argentina.", "answer": "<b> Falkland</b>s (Islands) War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A 1978 measure in this state restricted property-tax reassessments, and in 1994 it passed a referendum barring unauthorized immigrants from receiving social services. This state, which passed Propositions 13 and 187, was once governed by Pete Wilson and conducted a 2003 recall election which removed Democrat Gray Davis from office. For ten points, name this Western state which Arnold Schwarzenegger led for eight years from Sacramento.", "answer": "<b> California</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In one of this director\u2019s films, Colonel Dax defends his troops after they refuse to conduct a suicidal charge on enemy lines during World War I. This director\u2019s collaborations with Kirk Douglas include the aforementioned<em> Paths of Glory</em>, as well as a film following the Roman gladiator, Spartacus. In another of this man\u2019s movies, Peter Sellers plays 3 different roles, including the title handicapped, former-Nazi scientist. For ten points, name this American anti-war director of<em> Dr. Strangelove</em>, as well as<em> 2001: A</em> <em>Space Odyssey</em>.", "answer": "Stanley<b> Kubrick</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {"question": "This country attempted to defend itself with the Metaxas Line, and this country\u2019s seizure of Smyrna led to the War of Turkish Independence. Alexander Ypsilanti\u2019s independence movement in this country was aided by a foreign fleet, which fought the Ottomans at the Battle of Navarino, and a painting by Eugene Delacroix depicts this country \u201cExpiring on the Ruins of Missolonghi,\u201d the same city where Lord Byron died fighting for this country. For ten points, name this country which won its independence from the Ottomans, and has its capital at Athens.", "answer": "<b> Greece</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Juana Navarro Alsbury was brought to this location by her cousin and may have tried to surrender it. Courier James Allen is the last confirmed man to have (+) left this building, in which Susanna Dickinson hid in a church sacristy. James (*)</b> Bowie and Davy Crockett died at, for ten points, what San Antonio mission, the site of an 1836 battle where every Texan soldier was killed by Santa Anna\u2019s army?", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Alamo</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man, who advocated for Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence towards a northern neighbor, ordered the annexation of Goa from Portugal in 1961\u2019s Operation Vijay. This leader of the (+) Congress Party and rival of Muhammad Ali Jinnah\u2019s Muslim League gave the (*)</b> \u201cTryst with Destiny\u201d speech on the eve of his nation\u2019s independence from Great Britain in 1947. For ten points, name this father of Indira Gandhi and first Prime Minister of India.", "answer": "Jawaharlal<b> Nehru</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Michael O\u2019Rahilly was shot by a machine gun on Moore Street during this event, and it was described in a W.B. Yeats poem as \u201ca terrible beauty is born\u201d. James (+) Connolly lead a Citizen Army during this event, where its instigators had their headquarters at the General Post Office. The aftermath of this event led to the (*) </b> executions of Patrick Pearse and Roger Casement and saw the rise of the Sinn Fein Party. For ten points, name this 1916 uprising in Ireland named after a Christian holiday.", "answer": "<b> Easter Rising</b> or<b> Easter Rebellion</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>One scientist from this country gives his name to the excretory system of spiders and is considered the father of microscopic anatomy. One scientist from this country discovered</b> <b>\u201canimal (+)</b> <b>electricity;\u201d another scientist from this country built on that discovery to</b> <b>electricity;\u201d another scientist from this country built on that discovery to</b> <b>electricity;\u201d another scientist from this country built on that discovery to</b> <b>invent the first electrochemical battery.</b> <b>invent the first electrochemical battery.</b> <b>(*)</b> Alessandro Volta worked in, for ten points, what country where Galileo studied physics by dropping balls off the Leaning Tower of Pisa?", "answer": "<b> Italy</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This institution, led by August von Galen, opposed the Action T4 euthanasia program. Eugenio Pacelli was the chief negotiator for one treaty that led to recognition of this entity.</b> <b>The Centre Party supported this entity during (+)</b> <b>Bismarck\u2019s time as Chancellor.</b> <b>The</b> <b>document Mit brennender Sorge condemned attacks on this institution by (*)</b> Nazi Germany. For ten points, name this institution officially recognized by Nazi Germany after the Reichskonkordat, often criticized for not doing enough to stop the Holocaust under its leader, Pope Pius XII.", "answer": "Roman<b> Catholic Church</b>  (1) <b>Bill Moyers and Richard Goodwin worked on this project, whose budget was</b> <b>drawn up by Kermit Gordon. This program was first elucidated at a speech in Athens,</b> <b>Ohio, though its specific goals were laid out at the University of (+)</b> <b>Michigan.</b> <b>The Voting Rights Act and Economic Opportunity Act were created as part of this program, which succeeded the (*)</b> \u201cNew Frontier\u201d program. For ten points, name this broad range of social programs enacted by Lyndon Johnson. ANSWER:<b> Great Society</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}